<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Eviction Lab</title>
    <link>/updates/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Eviction Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/updates/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Habitat for Humanity Annual Awards Banquet</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-09-26-habitat-for-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 22:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-09-26-habitat-for-humanity/</guid>
      <description>Keynote Speaker: Matthew Desmond.
The Annual Awards Banquet honors outstanding individuals serving Habitat for Humanity of Michigan and their communities. The event features a Reception that raises funds to support Habitat Michigan. Habitat for Humanity of Michigan is a State Support Organization affiliated with Habitat for Humanity International and supports more than 60 local Michigan affiliates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WHEDA Conference</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-08-21-wheda/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 22:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-08-21-wheda/</guid>
      <description>Keynote Speaker: Matthew Desmond.
Join developers, syndicators, property managers, community leaders, industry experts and economic development professions for a day of learning sessions and collaboration to strengthen Wisconsin by expanding economic development and affordable multifamily housing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arlington Reads - &#34;Evicted&#34; by Matthew Desmond</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-05-17-arlington-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 22:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-05-17-arlington-library/</guid>
      <description>Matthew Desmond takes readers into the poorest neighborhoods of Milwaukee and tells the stories of eight families who struggle to keep a roof over their heads as they face extreme poverty, eviction and economic exploitation.
The fates of these families are in the hands of two landlords: Sherrena Tarver, a former schoolteacher turned inner-city entrepreneur, and Tobin Charney, who runs one of the worst trailer parks in Milwaukee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home and Hope: A Community Call to Action</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-05-16-jfsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 22:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-05-16-jfsm/</guid>
      <description>As part of its 150th Anniversary Celebration, Jewish Family Services (JFS) convenes community stakeholders to address the urgent need for safe and affordable housing, which has emerged as a leading social justice issue of our time.
JFS proudly welcomes Professor Matthew Desmond, whose local research, as chronicled in the Pulitzer-Prize-winning book, Evicted – Poverty and Profit in the American City, cast a spotlight on a complex problem that demands collaborative solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pathstone Presents: Provoking Thought</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-05-09-pathstone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 22:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-05-09-pathstone/</guid>
      <description>Building on our nearly five decades of success in Community Development, Workforce Development and Emergency Support services, PathStone is excited to launch PathStone Presents - Provoking Thought!, an opportunity to meet and interact with thought leaders engaged in addressing persistent poverty. Our inaugural luncheon will feature Dr. Matthew Desmond, Pulitzer Prize-winning author of Evicted: Poverty and Profit in the American City”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tackling Poverty Today</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-05-08-uja-federation-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 22:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-05-08-uja-federation-ny/</guid>
      <description>Join UJA-Federation and other leaders in the nonprofit, public, and for-profit sectors as we come together to learn, foster collaborations, and strategize about how to best address poverty in the greater New York community today.
Featured topics:
 Social enterprises addressing housing, hunger, and unemployment Groundbreaking government policies aimed at fighting poverty Tackling poverty through technological innovations Raising awareness through media and publishing  Keynote Speaker: Matthew Desmond Pulitzer Prize-Winning Author of Evicted: Poverty and Profit in the American City</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community in Crisis: Understanding Housing Insecurity</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-04-19-nku/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 22:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-04-19-nku/</guid>
      <description>Join Matthew Desmond, sociologist and Pulitzer Prize winner, as he discusses his powerful book, Evicted: Poverty and Profit in the American City.
RSVP: By April 18, 2018 to https://nku.eventsair.com/evicted/april19</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evicted: The Exhibition</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-04-14-national-building-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-04-14-national-building-museum/</guid>
      <description>The National Building Museum announces a new, ground-breaking exhibition exploring the causes and impacts of eviction.
A collaboration with Matthew Desmond, Professor of Sociology at Princeton University, a MacArthur “Genius” Fellow, and best-selling author, Evicted will offer an immersive experience bringing our visitors into the world of low-income renter eviction. With unique design elements and striking graphics, the exhibition will challenge adults and youth to face the enormity of a difficult subject, while providing context and a call to action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Eviction Data: Putting Residential Instability Numbers into Public Hands</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-04-12-urban-institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-04-12-urban-institute/</guid>
      <description>Join the Urban Institute for a discussion about a new data source on evictions in the US and its value for community response.
A shortage of affordable rental housing leaves millions of US households struggling to pay rent and avoid eviction. As documented by the sociologist and ethnographer Matthew Desmond and other housing scholars, evictions destabilize renters’ current housing and affect their work, health, education, and future housing options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Upcoming Events</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-10-10-neighbor-to-neighbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 18:33:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-10-10-neighbor-to-neighbor/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>