<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Student Researcher Bios on Eviction Lab</title>
    <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Student Researcher Bios on Eviction Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 20:43:49 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Henry Gomory</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/henry-gomory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/henry-gomory/</guid>
      <description>Henry is a first-year doctoral student in Sociology and Social Policy at Princeton University. He graduated from Harvard College in 2017 with a degree in Sociology and a minor in Statistics. For his undergraduate thesis, he studied how American cities have become unaffordable for many renters and the consequences that has had for social life in rent-burdened communities. Henry currently studies the causes of rising rent prices, the relationships between landlords and tenants, and how evictions affect community life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chase Hommeyer</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/chase-hommeyer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/chase-hommeyer/</guid>
      <description>Chase is a current undergraduate at Princeton University, pursuing a concentration in Sociology, with certificates in Statistics &amp;amp; Machine Learning and Theater. She’s a fellow at the Carl A Fields Center for Equality + Cultural Understanding, one of three student members on the Princeton Campus Iconography Committee, and worked at Princeton University Archives Library on a project called “Archiving Student Activism at Princeton.”A native of San Francisco, Chase is also a former downhill ski racer and 400 and 800m track runner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyojin Lee</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/hyojin-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/hyojin-lee/</guid>
      <description>Hyojin Lee is a research assistant with the Eviction Lab and an undergraduate at Princeton University. She is a prospective member of the Chemistry department; however, she is also interested in Roman language and culture, mathematics, and creative writing. She has previously researched computational methods in biology. When not working as a research assistant, she is most likely attending class, running by Lake Carnegie, or watching bad movies with her roommate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sejin Park</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/sejin-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/sejin-park/</guid>
      <description>Sejin is currently a senior at Princeton University studying Computer Science. Her main academic and personal interests lie at the intersection of technology and society, and she hopes to pursue a career studying and mediating the interaction of these two fields, especially in developing countries. At the Eviction Lab, she will be working closely with James researching legal infrastructure around housing by utilizing different computer science techniques such as natural language processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gillian Slee</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/gillian-slee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/gillian-slee/</guid>
      <description>Gillian Slee is a first-year doctoral student in Sociology and Social Policy at Princeton University. She graduated from Harvard College in 2016 with a degree in Social Studies and a minor in Psychology. In 2017, Gillian earned her M.Phil. degree in Criminology at the University of Cambridge where she was a Herchel Smith Harvard Scholar. For her undergraduate thesis, she conducted an ethnographic study of public defenders and their clients in New York City’s criminal courts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haley Zeng</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/haley-zeng/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/haley-zeng/</guid>
      <description>Haley is an undergraduate student at Princeton with interests in computer science and social sciences including sociology and psychology. In her work as a research assistant in the Eviction Lab, she hopes to be able to apply her programming skills to help illuminate eviction trends in the US. In her free time, Haley enjoys baking, swimming, and spending time with friends.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>