<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Student Researcher Bios on Eviction Lab</title>
    <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Student Researcher Bios on Eviction Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 20:43:49 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ndidi Anekwe</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/anekwe-ndidi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/anekwe-ndidi/</guid>
      <description>Ndidi is a junior at Princeton University concentrating in the Woodrow Wilson School and pursuing certificates in the Global Health Program and African American Studies. On campus, she serves as Co-Vice President of Insure Jersey, and volunteers with the HomeFront Health Initiative and Students for Prison Education and Reform (SPEAR). In her free time, she enjoys singing with the Trego ensemble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sean Duncan</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/duncan-sean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/duncan-sean/</guid>
      <description>Sean is a fourth year computer science student at Princeton University. On campus, he is a member of the varsity men’s Water Polo team and a swim instructor for Princeton University Aquatics. In his free time, he enjoys listening to/discovering new music and spending time outdoors. As a student researcher, he hopes to assist in further uncovering inequalities to the accessibility of affordable, quality rental housing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henry Gomory</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/gomory-henry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/gomory-henry/</guid>
      <description>Henry is a first-year doctoral student in Sociology and Social Policy at Princeton University. He graduated from Harvard College in 2017 with a degree in Sociology and a minor in Statistics. For his undergraduate thesis, he studied how American cities have become unaffordable for many renters and the consequences that has had for social life in rent-burdened communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Hendrickson</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/james-hendrickson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/james-hendrickson/</guid>
      <description>James is a graduate of the University of Michigan, where he obtained a B.A. in Public Policy with a focus on Applied Statistics and Labor Policy. He has worked for several public interest research and advocacy groups, such as the ACLU and the Economic Growth Institute, where he developed a deep interest in the intersection of statistical analysis and policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gracie Himmelstein</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/himmelstein-gracie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/himmelstein-gracie/</guid>
      <description>Gracie is a doctoral candidate in Demography and Social Policy at Princeton University, and a medical student at Mount Sinai School of Medicine. She graduated with an AB from Princeton in 2012 in Public Policy and International Affairs. Gracie studies health disparities, and how social inequality is reflected in, and perpetuated by, the health care system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lillian Leung</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/lillian-leung/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/lillian-leung/</guid>
      <description>Lillian is a first-year doctoral student in Sociology and Social Policy at Princeton University. She graduated in 2017 from New York University’s Stern School of Business, where she studied Economics and Global Business. Prior to her graduate studies, Lillian was a research specialist at the Eviction Lab, where she helped collect, clean, and analyze eviction records.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matt Mleczko</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/mleczko-matt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/mleczko-matt/</guid>
      <description>Matt is a doctoral student in Population Studies and Social Policy at Princeton University. He graduated with his B.A. in Economics and Political Science from the University of Notre Dame in 2015. Before beginning his studies at Princeton, Matt worked as a research assistant and programmer at Mathematica Policy Research, where he developed an interest in housing policy and segregation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott Overbey</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/overbey-scott/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/overbey-scott/</guid>
      <description>Scott Overbey is a junior in the Economics Department at Princeton University pursuing certificates in Statistics/Machine Learning, Political Economy, and Urban Studies. His research interests generally cover poverty, housing, and public finance in the United States and what government, specifically at a local level, can do to address social ills. As a proud Cincinnati native, he hopes to use this research to impact local policy making in his hometown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MaryAnn Placheril</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/placheril-maryann/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/placheril-maryann/</guid>
      <description>MaryAnn is a junior in the Woodrow Wilson School, pursuing certificates in African American Studies and Statistics and Machine Learning. On campus, she is on the board of the Princeton Student Events Committee and is the Executive Director of Princeton Model Congress. She’s interested in issues of homelessness, tenant rights, and broadly in the intersection of statistics and the law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devin Q. Rutan</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/rutan-devin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 03:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/rutan-devin/</guid>
      <description>Devin Q. Rutan is a first-year Ph.D. student in Princeton’s Sociology Department and is affiliated with the Office of Population Research. He is interested in the re-production of spatial inequality and the persistence of residential segregation. In 2016, he received a Bachelor of Philosophy in Urban Studies from the University of Pittsburgh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naomi Shifrin</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/shifrin-naomi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 03:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/shifrin-naomi/</guid>
      <description>Naomi is a third-year undergraduate in the Sociology department, pursuing a certificate in the Center for Human Values. Prior to beginning at Princeton, she lived in Dakar, Senegal in a year of cultural immersion, fostering an interest in the relationship between development interventions and how they interact with the complexities of people’s lived experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gillian Slee</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/slee-gillian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/slee-gillian/</guid>
      <description>Gillian Slee is a first-year doctoral student in Sociology and Social Policy at Princeton University. She graduated from Harvard College in 2016 with a degree in Social Studies and a minor in Psychology. In 2017, Gillian earned her M.Phil. degree in Criminology at the University of Cambridge where she was a Herchel Smith Harvard Scholar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael Zhang</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/zhang-michael/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/zhang-michael/</guid>
      <description>Michael Zhang is currently a post-doctoral researcher in the Department of Computer Science. He earned a PhD in statistics at the University of Texas at Austin in 2018.
His research interests include probabilistic machine learning, scalable computation, Bayesian non-parametrics and its applications to the social sciences.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>