<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Eviction Lab on Eviction Lab</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Eviction Lab on Eviction Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/page-text/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/page-text/introduction/</guid>
      <description>Today, the majority of poor renting families in America spend over half of their income on housing costs, and eviction is transforming their lives. Yet little is known about the prevalence, causes, and consequences of housing insecurity.
The Eviction Lab is a team of researchers, students, and website architects who believe that a stable, affordable home is central to human flourishing and economic mobility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matthew Desmond</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/matthew-desmond/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/matthew-desmond/</guid>
      <description>Matthew Desmond is the Maurice P. During Professor of Sociology at Princeton University. After receiving his Ph.D. in 2010 from the University of Wisconsin at Madison, he joined the Harvard Society of Fellows as a Junior Fellow. He is the author of four books, including Evicted: Poverty and Profit in the American City (2016), which won the Pulitzer Prize, National Book Critics Circle Award, and Carnegie Medal, and PEN / John Kenneth Galbraith Award for Nonfiction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graham MacDonald</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/citizen-researchers/graham-macdonald/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/citizen-researchers/graham-macdonald/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Background</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/page-text/background/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/page-text/background/</guid>
      <description>Matthew Desmond started studying housing, poverty, and eviction in 2008, living and working alongside poor tenants and their landlords in Milwaukee, Wisconsin. Combining ethnographic fieldwork with original statistical analyses, Desmond discovered that eviction was incredibly prevalent in low-income communities and functioned as a cause, not just a condition, of poverty. This work was summarized in his book, Evicted: Poverty and Profit in the American City (2016).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Work</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/page-text/work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/page-text/work/</guid>
      <description>Through this website, the Eviction Lab has made nationwide eviction data publicly available and accessible. We hope this data is used by policymakers, community organizers, journalists, educators, non-profit organizations, students, and citizens interested in understanding more about housing, eviction, and poverty in their own backyards. You can look at evictions over time, map evictions in the United States, compare the eviction rates of different neighborhoods, cities, or states, and generate custom reports about America’s eviction epidemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kyle Nelson</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/citizen-researchers/kyle-nelson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/citizen-researchers/kyle-nelson/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aaron Dulles, esq.</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/citizen-researchers/aaron-dulles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/citizen-researchers/aaron-dulles/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tim Thomas</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/citizen-researchers/tim-thomas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/citizen-researchers/tim-thomas/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flatland—KCPT</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/citizen-researchers/flatland-kc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/citizen-researchers/flatland-kc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oksana Mironova &amp; Thomas J. Waters</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/citizen-researchers/oksana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/citizen-researchers/oksana/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jonathan Pyle</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/citizen-researchers/jonathan-pyle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/citizen-researchers/jonathan-pyle/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helena Najm</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/helena-najm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/helena-najm/</guid>
      <description>Helena received her HBSc from the University of Toronto in 2017, and graduated from Columbia University&amp;rsquo;s MA in Global Thought program in 2019. She has worked at the nexus of health, politics and social inequality in academic and public service capacities, and is broadly interested in researching social welfare policy, urban inequality, citizenship and social stratification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ndidi Anekwe</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/anekwe-ndidi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/anekwe-ndidi/</guid>
      <description>Ndidi is a junior at Princeton University concentrating in the Woodrow Wilson School and pursuing certificates in the Global Health Program and African American Studies. On campus, she serves as Co-Vice President of Insure Jersey, and volunteers with the HomeFront Health Initiative and Students for Prison Education and Reform (SPEAR). In her free time, she enjoys singing with the Trego ensemble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terry Cannon</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/citizen-researchers/terry-cannon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/citizen-researchers/terry-cannon/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sean Duncan</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/duncan-sean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/duncan-sean/</guid>
      <description>Sean is a fourth year computer science student at Princeton University. On campus, he is a member of the varsity men’s Water Polo team and a swim instructor for Princeton University Aquatics. In his free time, he enjoys listening to/discovering new music and spending time outdoors. As a student researcher, he hopes to assist in further uncovering inequalities to the accessibility of affordable, quality rental housing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anne Kat Alexander</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/anne-kat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/anne-kat/</guid>
      <description>Anne Kat is a recent graduate of Brandeis University, where she received a BA in English and Creative Writing. She is the Faculty Assistant in the Eviction Lab. Her bachelor&amp;rsquo;s thesis considered issues of chronic low mood and hopelessness in early modern poetry, which may be why she sticks to reading murder mysteries and YA these days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henry Gomory</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/gomory-henry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/gomory-henry/</guid>
      <description>Henry is a first-year doctoral student in Sociology and Social Policy at Princeton University. He graduated from Harvard College in 2017 with a degree in Sociology and a minor in Statistics. For his undergraduate thesis, he studied how American cities have become unaffordable for many renters and the consequences that has had for social life in rent-burdened communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alieza Durana</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/alieza-durana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/alieza-durana/</guid>
      <description>Alieza Durana is a journalist and media impact expert helping to increase the reach and impact of stories. Her passion for addressing social and income inequalities has taken her around the world in pursuit of the data and stories that can move policy and culture forward. She writes and leads media strategy for The Eviction Lab in partnership with the Economic Hardship Reporting Project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LAVAR EDMONDS</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/lavar-edmonds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/lavar-edmonds/</guid>
      <description>Lavar Edmonds is a research specialist with the Eviction Lab. Guided by experiences as a high school math teacher, his research broadly centers around inequality, particularly in education. In college, he worked as the data analyst for the school’s Student Transition Program, studying academic outcomes for first-generation and traditionally underrepresented minority students at the university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Hendrickson</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/james-hendrickson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/james-hendrickson/</guid>
      <description>James is a graduate of the University of Michigan, where he obtained a B.A. in Public Policy with a focus on Applied Statistics and Labor Policy. He has worked for several public interest research and advocacy groups, such as the ACLU and the Economic Growth Institute, where he developed a deep interest in the intersection of statistical analysis and policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gracie Himmelstein</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/himmelstein-gracie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/himmelstein-gracie/</guid>
      <description>Gracie is a doctoral candidate in Demography and Social Policy at Princeton University, and a medical student at Mount Sinai School of Medicine. She graduated with an AB from Princeton in 2012 in Public Policy and International Affairs. Gracie studies health disparities, and how social inequality is reflected in, and perpetuated by, the health care system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joe Fish</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/joe-fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/joe-fish/</guid>
      <description>Joe received his bachelor’s degree in Economics and Applied Math from Macalester College. A San Francisco native, his senior thesis used a survival analysis framework to explore the effect of zip code level tech growth on San Francisco eviction rates. As a researcher, he hopes to establish causal relationships between the effects of wealth consolidation and income inequality on eviction rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Minton</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/web-team-bios/james-minton/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 00:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/web-team-bios/james-minton/</guid>
      <description>James Minton is a designer and web developer committed to projects with a focus on public service and social justice. He holds degrees in photography, multimedia arts and psychology. Most recent projects include work with NYU School of Medicine, and developing Justshelter.org in conjunction with Matthew Desmond’s release of Evicted: Poverty and Profit in the American City.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABBY BAJUNIEMI</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/web-team-bios/abby-bajuniemi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 17:49:52 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/web-team-bios/abby-bajuniemi/</guid>
      <description>Abby Bajuniemi is a former visiting professor of Linguistics and Spanish at Macalester College. She completed a PhD in Hispanic and Lusophone Literatures, Cultures and Linguistics at the University of Minnesota, where her research interests centered on language acquisition and sociolinguistics. She translates that love of language structure and teaching into a passion for accessibility and inclusivity in design and content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NOELE LUSANO</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/web-team-bios/noele-lusano/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 17:52:48 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/web-team-bios/noele-lusano/</guid>
      <description>Noele is a visual designer and photographer with 10+ years’ experience designing for the web, specializing in branding, creative direction, UI design and product development. She studied photography and design at London College of Communication. Drawn to complex design problems that seek to improve quality of life, she has contributed to a number of projects and redesigns in tech and ecommerce, and recently nonprofit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lane Olson</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/web-team-bios/lane-olson/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 01:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/web-team-bios/lane-olson/</guid>
      <description>Lane Olson holds a Bachelor of Science in computing science, with distinction, from the University of Alberta. With nearly two decades of web design and development experience, Lane has created interactive experiences for art galleries, universities, and highly acclaimed online courses. Through his previous work creating data visualizations and maps for online courses, like Mountains 101 and Indigenous Canada, Lane has developed a keen interest in creating interactive tools that are effective and easy to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patrick Sier</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/web-team-bios/patrick-sier/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 17:58:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/web-team-bios/patrick-sier/</guid>
      <description>Patrick received a Bachelor of Arts in public policy from the University of Michigan. This background has informed his work as a web developer, most recently creating tools for evaluations and interactive dashboards at a university research center. He has experience in data visualization and analysis as well as civic technology projects involving tenants’ rights and the justice system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christopher Groskopf</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/web-team-bios/chris-groskopf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 17:58:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/web-team-bios/chris-groskopf/</guid>
      <description>Christopher Groskopf is a journalist and software engineer who lives in the piney woods of East Texas. For the Eviction Lab, Chris lent his expertise in information design and programming toward creation of our eviction mapping strategy, as well as recruitment of technical talent. Currently he&amp;rsquo;s building tools for solving problems with public data at Enigma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jonny Miller</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/web-team-bios/jonny-miller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 18:43:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/web-team-bios/jonny-miller/</guid>
      <description>Jonny brings over 17 years of experience in the fields of web development, design, UI/UX, and project management to the team. Previously he worked with one of western Canada’s largest online education providers, where he was the UI/UX Team Lead, and a web developer Jack-of-all. As the CMS Specialist at Eviction Lab, Jonny is inspired to be working with modern content delivery services such as Netlify and Hugo, and the general world of “JAMstack” architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natalie Repetto</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/web-team-bios/natalie-repetto/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 17:52:48 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/web-team-bios/natalie-repetto/</guid>
      <description>Natalie studied economics and sociology at Mills College in Oakland, where she received her Bachelor of Arts in Political, Legal and Economic Analysis. With over a decade working in a variety of industries, from real estate and sales to finance and non-profit, Natalie understands the importance of efficiency and effective management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley Gromis</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/ashley-gromis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:52:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/ashley-gromis/</guid>
      <description>Ashley joined the Eviction Lab as a postdoctoral research associate after completing her Ph.D. in Sociology at the University of California, Los Angeles. Her dissertation research examined the formation and consequences of spatial clustering of children with non-medical exemptions to school vaccine requirements in California. More broadly, her research interests focus on how social networks and local communities provide the social context for individual decisions and events that aggregate to form macro-level patterns across space and time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lillian Leung</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/lillian-leung/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/lillian-leung/</guid>
      <description>Lillian is a first-year doctoral student in Sociology and Social Policy at Princeton University. She graduated in 2017 from New York University’s Stern School of Business, where she studied Economics and Global Business. Prior to her graduate studies, Lillian was a research specialist at the Eviction Lab, where she helped collect, clean, and analyze eviction records.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matt Mleczko</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/mleczko-matt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/mleczko-matt/</guid>
      <description>Matt is a doctoral student in Population Studies and Social Policy at Princeton University. He graduated with his B.A. in Economics and Political Science from the University of Notre Dame in 2015. Before beginning his studies at Princeton, Matt worked as a research assistant and programmer at Mathematica Policy Research, where he developed an interest in housing policy and segregation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peter Hepburn</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/peter-hepburn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/peter-hepburn/</guid>
      <description>Peter joined the Eviction Lab as an Associate Professional Specialist after completing his doctorate in Sociology and Demography at the University of California, Berkeley. Peter&amp;rsquo;s research examines the ways that employment practices and public policies affect children and low-income families. His dissertation analyzed the relationships between parental working schedules, household structure, and childcare arrangements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aparna Howlader</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/aparna-howlader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/aparna-howlader/</guid>
      <description>Aparna completed her Ph.D. at the Department of Agricultural and Consumer Economics at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign. Her dissertation research studies the relationship between land conservation policies and economic development. A large part of her current research is devoted to studying the extent to which early land conservation policies in the USA affect later economic and environmental conditions in the Great Plains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott Overbey</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/overbey-scott/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/overbey-scott/</guid>
      <description>Scott Overbey is a junior in the Economics Department at Princeton University pursuing certificates in Statistics/Machine Learning, Political Economy, and Urban Studies. His research interests generally cover poverty, housing, and public finance in the United States and what government, specifically at a local level, can do to address social ills. As a proud Cincinnati native, he hopes to use this research to impact local policy making in his hometown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Katie Krywokulski</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/katie-krywokulski/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 03:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/katie-krywokulski/</guid>
      <description>Katie received an MA in English Language and Literature from the University of Chicago in 2016. Her research interests included religion and the literary history of consent eighteenth and nineteenth century America. She taught courses titled “Death and Dying in Early America” and “Women Possessed: Religion, Gender, and Sexuality,” as well as first year writing classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MaryAnn Placheril</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/placheril-maryann/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/placheril-maryann/</guid>
      <description>MaryAnn is a junior in the Woodrow Wilson School, pursuing certificates in African American Studies and Statistics and Machine Learning. On campus, she is on the board of the Princeton Student Events Committee and is the Executive Director of Princeton Model Congress. She’s interested in issues of homelessness, tenant rights, and broadly in the intersection of statistics and the law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do the red bubbles mean?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q102-redbubbles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q102-redbubbles/</guid>
      <description>The red bubbles represent the eviction rate or eviction filing rate. Bigger bubbles are bigger numbers. Smaller bubbles are smaller numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Eviction Lab?</title>
      <link>/methods/page-content/102-what-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/page-content/102-what-is/</guid>
      <description>The Eviction Lab is a research organization dedicated to studying the prevalence, causes, and consequences of eviction. The database it has built represents the largest accumulation of U.S. court records related to eviction ever compiled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devin Q. Rutan</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/rutan-devin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 03:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/rutan-devin/</guid>
      <description>Devin Q. Rutan is a first-year Ph.D. student in Princeton’s Sociology Department and is affiliated with the Office of Population Research. He is interested in the re-production of spatial inequality and the persistence of residential segregation. In 2016, he received a Bachelor of Philosophy in Urban Studies from the University of Pittsburgh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renee Louis</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/renee-louis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/renee-louis/</guid>
      <description>Renee received her B.A. from Princeton University where she concentrated in Sociology and received a certificate in Statistics and Machine Learning. Her undergraduate research endeavors ranged from examining nonprofit Twitter behavior, analyzing attitudes towards inequality across forty years of survey data, as well as studying the experiences of student dining hall workers on campus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What data has the Eviction Lab collected?</title>
      <link>/methods/page-content/110-what-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/page-content/110-what-data/</guid>
      <description>The data we collected is comprised of formal eviction records from 48 states and the District of Columbia. Eviction records include information related to an eviction court case, such as defendant and plaintiff names, the defendant’s address, monetary judgment information, and an outcome for the case. We combined these records with demographic information from the Census to paint a better picture of the areas in which these evictions are happening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does the blue mean?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q110-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q110-blue/</guid>
      <description>The blue represents the concentration of the Census value you selected. For example, if you selected “population,” a darker blue means a higher population and a lighter blue means a lower population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naomi Shifrin</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/shifrin-naomi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 03:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/shifrin-naomi/</guid>
      <description>Naomi is a third-year undergraduate in the Sociology department, pursuing a certificate in the Center for Human Values. Prior to beginning at Princeton, she lived in Dakar, Senegal in a year of cultural immersion, fostering an interest in the relationship between development interventions and how they interact with the complexities of people’s lived experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are these all the evictions that have taken place?</title>
      <link>/methods/page-content/120-all-evictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/page-content/120-all-evictions/</guid>
      <description>No. Evictions can happen outside of the courtroom, as when landlords pay renters to leave or execute illegal lockouts. There is some evidence that “informal evictions” are more common than “formal”, court-ordered evictions. Informal evictions are not captured in our dataset. Moreover, while we have tried to collect every recorded court-ordered eviction case, going back to 2000, some records were unavailable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many locations can I compare in the map?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q120-locations-in-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q120-locations-in-map/</guid>
      <description>You can compare three locations at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gillian Slee</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/slee-gillian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/slee-gillian/</guid>
      <description>Gillian Slee is a first-year doctoral student in Sociology and Social Policy at Princeton University. She graduated from Harvard College in 2016 with a degree in Social Studies and a minor in Psychology. In 2017, Gillian earned her M.Phil. degree in Criminology at the University of Cambridge where she was a Herchel Smith Harvard Scholar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How did you collect the data?</title>
      <link>/methods/page-content/130-how-collected/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/page-content/130-how-collected/</guid>
      <description>First, we requested a bulk report of cases directly from courts. These reports included all recorded information related to eviction-related cases. Second, we conducted automated record collection from online portals, via web scraping and text parsing protocols. Third, we partnered with companies that carry out manual collection of records, going directly into the courts and extracting the relevant case information by hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael Zhang</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/zhang-michael/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/student-researcher-bios/zhang-michael/</guid>
      <description>Michael Zhang is currently a post-doctoral researcher in the Department of Computer Science. He earned a PhD in statistics at the University of Texas at Austin in 2018.
His research interests include probabilistic machine learning, scalable computation, Bayesian non-parametrics and its applications to the social sciences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where do your data come from?</title>
      <link>/methods/page-content/140-whence-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/page-content/140-whence-data/</guid>
      <description>We have accumulated over 80 million records related to eviction. The Eviction Lab directly collected court records from 12 states. But many states either did not centralize their eviction data or were unwilling to release this information. Accordingly, the Eviction Lab then purchased more comprehensive datasets of public eviction records from two companies: LexisNexis Risk Solutions and American Information Research Services Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where does the eviction data come from?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q140-data-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q140-data-source/</guid>
      <description>We have accumulated over 80 million records related to eviction. The Eviction Lab directly collected court records from 13 states. But many states either did not centralize their eviction data or were unwilling to release this information. Accordingly, the Eviction Lab then purchased more comprehensive datasets of public eviction records from two companies: LexisNexis Risk Solutions and American Information Research Services Inc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is there an empty bubble for my chosen location?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q140-empty-bubble/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q140-empty-bubble/</guid>
      <description>For locations with an empty bubble, there is no available data for the selected year. Data for that location may exist for other years, however.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where does the Census data come from?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q141.3-census/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q141.3-census/</guid>
      <description>We used estimates of renter-occupied households from the 2000 and 2010 U.S. Censuses and ESRI Business Analyst 2016. For further details on the renter-occupied household variable, please read our Methodology Report (PDF).
We used the following surveys for other demographic variables listed on the website and data download:
Years AssociatedSurvey(s) Used  2000-20042000 Census   2005-20092005-2009 ACS 5-Year Estimates   20102010 Census for Population estimates; 2008-2012 ACS 5-Year for all other estimates   2011-20162011-2015 ACS 5-Year Estimates   See our data dictionary for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many people are evicted nationwide?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q155-5-us-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q155-5-us-stats/</guid>
      <description>See the following table:
 Year Renter Occupied Households Eviction Filings Evictions Eviction Filing Rate Eviction Rate   2000 19327822 1159168 518873 6 2.68   2001 27438838 1750452 754652 6.38 2.75   2002 29982440 2085491 864918 6.96 2.88   2003 30330222 2134014 910361 7.04 3   2004 30784432 2177018 940817 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is my area missing eviction information?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q142.8-missing-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q142.8-missing-info/</guid>
      <description>We’ve collected over 80 million eviction records going back several years, but we still don’t have them all! We will continue our effort to provide the most comprehensive data on evictions in America and invite you to stay tuned for updates to our dataset by signing up for our email list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does my state have an eviction filing rate but not an eviction rate?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q143-filing-not-eviction-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q143-filing-not-eviction-rate/</guid>
      <description>Because you live in Arkansas, North Dakota, Alaska, or South Dakota, states for which we do not have enough individual-level eviction records to make an estimate. In these states, we can display reported statistics about eviction filings, however. For more details about how we handled data from different sources see our Methods page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My area shows a high filing or eviction rate. What does this mean?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q144-high-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q144-high-rate/</guid>
      <description>On the map, we have indicated with the symbol Census tracts and block groups with filing and eviction rates in the top 1%. There are areas with high rates because housing insecurity is especially acute there. But there are other considerations as well.
Remember that filing and eviction rates are calculated by dividing the number of filings or evictions in an area by the number of renter homes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My state shows a low filing or eviction rate. What does this mean?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q145-low-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q145-low-rate/</guid>
      <description>On the map, we have indicated with the symbol states with underestimated eviction counts. Of course, some places have low eviction rates because there are few renters living there or because there are very few evictions. But some states and the District of Columbia have underestimated eviction counts in our dataset for a variety of reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are the filing and eviction rates similar in my area?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q146-similar-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q146-similar-rates/</guid>
      <description>It’s probably not because almost all eviction cases end in eviction but because of our inability to collect all eviction cases in your area. We attempted to collect every court record related to eviction—including filings that didn’t result in eviction—but some of our data sources prioritized cases that ended in a civil judgment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does &#34;auto&#34; mean in the Map Level menu?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q147-auto-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q147-auto-map/</guid>
      <description>Selecting &amp;ldquo;auto&amp;rdquo; enables you to zoom through the geographic levels (states, counties, cities, census tracts, and block groups) automatically. You can also select your desired geographic level from the same dropdown menu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the difference between a filing rate and an eviction rate?</title>
      <link>/methods/page-content/150-filing-vs-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/page-content/150-filing-vs-rate/</guid>
      <description>A “filing rate” is the ratio of the number of evictions filed in an area over the number of renter-occupied homes in that area. An “eviction rate” is the subset of those homes that received an eviction judgment in which renters were ordered to leave. The filing rate also counts all eviction cases filed in an area, including multiple cases filed against the same address in the same year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many locations can I compare in the graphs?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q151-how-many-locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q151-how-many-locations/</guid>
      <description>You can compare up to 3 locations. The U.S. average eviction rate is also included by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the difference between an eviction and an eviction filing?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q152-filings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q152-filings/</guid>
      <description>An eviction filing is the result of a landlord filing a case in court to have a tenant removed from a property. An eviction is a judgment from the court that a tenant should be removed. As not every eviction filing results in an eviction, the filing rate will always be higher in a given area than the eviction rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What kinds of locations can I enter into the search bar?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q153-search-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q153-search-bar/</guid>
      <description>You can search by state, county, or city. You can also search for any listed address in America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I downloaded data for my city/place, and it says I have less than one eviction/filing. What does that mean?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q154-places-below-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q154-places-below-one/</guid>
      <description>While other units of geography are all connected (block groups, census tracts, counties, etc.), place boundaries are separate—requiring evictions to be aggregated and estimated differently. In many cases, the estimates of eviction are non-whole numbers (e.g., 0.4, 31.5, 100.6).
One feature of this strategy is that some low population areas could have less than one eviction estimated for that place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Rent Burden, and why is it capped at 50%?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q155-rent-burden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q155-rent-burden/</guid>
      <description>Rent Burden is the percentage of household income spent on rent in a given area. The U.S. Census Bureau only calculates this statistic up to 50%&amp;mdash;any number above that is listed as &amp;ldquo;50% or more.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does the site share when I click on Twitter or Facebook?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q156-social-share/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q156-social-share/</guid>
      <description>You can share links to any of our pages via social share buttons. From our Map and Eviction Rankings pages, you can share customized links preloaded with the locations and data you have selected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I embed the map in my blog or website?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q157-embed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q157-embed/</guid>
      <description>You can embed the map in your website or blog using the provided embed code. Under the &amp;ldquo;share&amp;rdquo; section of the map &amp;amp; data page, click the link button to grab the code. You can then paste that code into your own site. The map will show the eviction and census data types you selected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What reports can I download, and what can I do with them?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q158-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q158-reports/</guid>
      <description>Reports, which are customized to display the same data and locations you&amp;rsquo;ve selected via the map and search, are designed as tools to support research and activism. You can download
 An Excel spreadsheet containing raw data A Powerpoint presentation to share in your classroom, lecture, or meeting A PDF file, which also contains a fact sheet about evictions, for wide sharing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How did you calculate the filing/eviction rate?</title>
      <link>/methods/page-content/160-calculate-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/page-content/160-calculate-rate/</guid>
      <description>For the denominator of our rate, we used the number of occupied renting households in each area. Information on the number of renter homes in an area comes from the U.S. Census and ESRI Business Analyst demographic estimates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is &#34;Get More Data&#34;?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q160-get-more-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q160-get-more-data/</guid>
      <description>Get More Data will take you to a page where you can search for and download large data sets for the entire United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I can download imputed or non-imputed data. What does this mean?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q162-imputed-non/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q162-imputed-non/</guid>
      <description>Because these data were collected manually from courts across the country, some areas are missing data over time. In other cases, statistical models indicated that there was too much variance in collection from one year to the next. In these cases, we filled in some of those gaps by “imputing” data based on a set of procedures listed in our Methodology Report (PDF).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What devices / browsers do you support?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q162-browsers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q162-browsers/</guid>
      <description>We support the last two major releases of Edge, Chrome, Firefox, and Safari. We also support Internet Explorer 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many places are listed in your Eviction Rankings?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q168-how-many-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q168-how-many-places/</guid>
      <description>Nearly 30,000 places&amp;mdash;cities, towns, villages, and unincorporated areas&amp;mdash;are included in our database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How did you clean the data?</title>
      <link>/methods/page-content/170-cleaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/page-content/170-cleaning/</guid>
      <description>To create the best estimates, all data we obtained underwent a rigorous cleaning protocol. This included formatting the data so that each observation represented a household; cleaning and standardizing the names and addresses; and dropping duplicate cases. The details of this process can be found in the Methodology Report (PDF).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How are “locations” in your rankings defined?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q176-rankings-locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q176-rankings-locations/</guid>
      <description>Locations in our rankings are drawn from the list of Census Places. They do not include counties or metro areas. For more information about Census Places, see the U.S. Census website (click here or here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why can&#39;t I find the place I&#39;m looking for in the rankings?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q172-cant-find/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q172-cant-find/</guid>
      <description>Our rankings visualization shows only the top 100 areas based on your selections. Using the search bar, however, you can find the ranking for any place in America.
If you cannot find a place via the search bar, it may not be a place listed in the Census, or it may be a kind of place (like a state or county) that is not ranked in this tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are places in Eviction Rankings divided into 3 different area types? What do these mean?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q175-area-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q175-area-types/</guid>
      <description>We chose to categorize places in our Rankings (as Large Cities, Mid-sized Cities, or Small Cities &amp;amp; Rural Areas) to allow for more meaningful comparisons among places with similar populations.
 Small Cities &amp;amp; Rural Areas are places with populations under 20,000. We rank 27,403 of these places. Examples: Clarksdale, MS; Fremont, OH</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do you report 2015 eviction rankings?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q178-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q178-2015/</guid>
      <description>Because that’s the most recent year with the most comprehensive data. Because data collection efforts are not centralized, it takes some time to collect all the evictions from a single year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How were you able to determine the amount of evictions in each neighborhood?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q180-evictions-amount/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q180-evictions-amount/</guid>
      <description>Eviction records contain addresses. We had these addresses geocoded and spatially joined by the Environmental Systems Research Institute (ESRI). This process allowed us to match each address record to a latitude and a longitude. Then, by overlaying the geographic boundaries on top of these points, we can observe how many evictions took place in that area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How were you able to determine the amount of evictions in each neighborhood?</title>
      <link>/methods/page-content/180-how-number-evictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/page-content/180-how-number-evictions/</guid>
      <description>Eviction records contain addresses. We had these addresses geocoded and spatially joined by the Environmental Systems Research Institute (ESRI). This process allowed us to match each address record to a latitude and a longitude. Then, by overlaying the geographic boundaries on top of these points, we can observe how many evictions took place in that area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For regions where you did not have comprehensive data, how did you estimate the eviction rate?</title>
      <link>/methods/page-content/190-estimate-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/page-content/190-estimate-rate/</guid>
      <description>We used a common practice for missing data called “imputation.” For more information on this, please see the Methodology Report (PDF).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How did you validate your estimates?</title>
      <link>/methods/page-content/200-validate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/page-content/200-validate/</guid>
      <description>We linked individual records from overlapping data sources. Through this procedure, we determined that the content of the records (e.g., address, name information) had a high rate of validity. In addition, we obtained statistics from 27 states, New York City, and the District of Columbia that gave us numbers of cases filed per year at the county level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is an eviction?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q200-what-is-eviction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q200-what-is-eviction/</guid>
      <description>An eviction happens when a landlord expels people from property he or she owns. Evictions are landlord-initiated involuntary moves that happen to renters, whereas foreclosures are involuntary moves that happen to homeowners when a bank or other lending agency repossesses a home.
In our data, an eviction is defined as an eviction judgment issued to a renting home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can I read a more thorough report on your methods?</title>
      <link>/methods/page-content/210-methods-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/page-content/210-methods-report/</guid>
      <description>Yes. You can download the full report (PDF) here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is an eviction rate and how is it calculated?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q210-eviction-rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q210-eviction-rate/</guid>
      <description>An eviction rate is the number of evictions per 100 renter homes in an area. An eviction rate of 5% means that 5 of every 100 renter homes faced eviction in the selected area that year.
Information on the number of renter homes in an area comes from the U.S. Census and ESRI Business Analyst demographic estimates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How were evictions calculated?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q221-evictions-calc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q221-evictions-calc/</guid>
      <description>Anim pariatur cliche reprehenderit, enim eiusmod high life accusamus terry richardson ad squid. Nihil anim keffiyeh helvetica, craft beer labore wes anderson cred nesciunt sapiente ea proident.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is an eviction filing?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q212-eviction-filing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q212-eviction-filing/</guid>
      <description>An eviction filing is the result of a landlord filing a case in court to have a tenant removed from a property.
Within our data, case information is recorded as separate actions with dates of each action. Our estimate of eviction filings is the total amount of cases each year with a first recorded action in that year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if I have more questions?</title>
      <link>/methods/page-content/220-more-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/page-content/220-more-questions/</guid>
      <description>We’re here to help. Please contact us via email at research@evictionlab.org.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you have any data on how many women, children, or the elderly are affected by eviction?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q240-demographics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q240-demographics/</guid>
      <description>Since eviction records do not include demographic information like age or gender, we do not have direct access to these numbers. However, local studies show that households with children are especially vulnerable to forced displacement. While we don&amp;rsquo;t have the full picture now, the Eviction Lab dataset enables users to create estimates on a scale that was previously impossible, and important questions like these can be addressed in future research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m a journalist, educator, or citizen/activist. How can I use your tools to find stories in the data, and educate people about eviction?</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/q250-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/q250-stories/</guid>
      <description>We have developed a Media Guide and Teacher’s Guide. We’ll be highlighting how journalists, teachers, community organizers, policymakers, and engaged citizens have used our data—both on our Facebook and Twitter accounts and our Updates pages. You can also download reading group guides for the book Evicted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard Methodology</title>
      <link>/covid-housing-scorecard-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 16:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-housing-scorecard-methods/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
To prevent the deleterious health consequences of eviction and an escalating economic crisis during the COVID-19 outbreak, U.S. states are beginning to pursue strategies to ensure safe, decent, and stable housing during and after the pandemic. To evaluate state responses, the Eviction Lab and Columbia Law School’s Professor Emily Benfer have developed a policy scorecard for each state, distilling the contents of thousands of newly-released emergency orders, declarations, and legislation into a clear set of critical measures included in, and left out of, state-level pandemic responses related to eviction and housing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Alabama</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/al/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/al/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Alaska</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/ak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/ak/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Arizona</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/az/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/az/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Arkansas</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/ar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/ar/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for California</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/ca/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Colorado</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/co/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/co/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Connecticut</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/ct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/ct/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Delaware</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/de/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/de/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for District of Columbia</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/dc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Florida</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/fl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/fl/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Georgia</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/ga/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/ga/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Hawaii</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/hi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/hi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Idaho</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/id/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/id/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Illinois</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/il/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/il/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Indiana</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/in/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/in/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Iowa</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/ia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/ia/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Kansas</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/ks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/ks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Kentucky</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/ky/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/ky/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Louisiana</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/la/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/la/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Maine</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/me/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Maryland</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/md/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/md/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Massachusetts</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/ma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/ma/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Michigan</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/mi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/mi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Minnesota</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/mn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/mn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Mississippi</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/ms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/ms/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Missouri</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/mo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/mo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Montana</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/mt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/mt/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Nebraska</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/ne/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/ne/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Nevada</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/nv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/nv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for New Hampshire</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/nh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/nh/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for New Jersey</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/nj/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/nj/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for New Mexico</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/nm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/nm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for New York</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/ny/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for North Carolina</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/nc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/nc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for North Dakota</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/nd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/nd/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Ohio</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/oh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/oh/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Oklahoma</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/ok/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/ok/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Oregon</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/or/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/or/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Pennsylvania</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/pa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/pa/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Rhode Island</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/ri/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/ri/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for South Carolina</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/sc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/sc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for South Dakota</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/sd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/sd/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Tennessee</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/tn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/tn/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Texas</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/tx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/tx/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Utah</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/ut/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/ut/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Vermont</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/vt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/vt/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Virginia</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/va/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/va/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Washington</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/wa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/wa/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for West Virginia</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/wv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/wv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Wisconsin</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/wi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/wi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard for Wyoming</title>
      <link>/covid-policy-scorecard/wy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-policy-scorecard/wy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 and Changing Eviction Policies Around the Nation</title>
      <link>/covid-eviction-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 16:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-eviction-policies/</guid>
      <description>As the world seeks to contain the COVID-19 pandemic, policymakers across the U.S. are responding to the heightened insecurity so many face.
This new table details where municipalities, states, and the federal government have taken action. We will be continually updating the table and welcome tips regarding what your community is putting into place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Habitat for Humanity Annual Awards Banquet</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-09-26-habitat-for-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 22:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-09-26-habitat-for-humanity/</guid>
      <description>Keynote Speaker: Matthew Desmond.
The Annual Awards Banquet honors outstanding individuals serving Habitat for Humanity of Michigan and their communities. The event features a Reception that raises funds to support Habitat Michigan. Habitat for Humanity of Michigan is a State Support Organization affiliated with Habitat for Humanity International and supports more than 60 local Michigan affiliates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WHEDA Conference</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-08-21-wheda/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 22:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-08-21-wheda/</guid>
      <description>Keynote Speaker: Matthew Desmond.
Join developers, syndicators, property managers, community leaders, industry experts and economic development professions for a day of learning sessions and collaboration to strengthen Wisconsin by expanding economic development and affordable multifamily housing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article: Eviction Data Can Keep Cities from “Designing Policy in the Dark”</title>
      <link>/updates/blog/how-housing-matters-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 08:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/blog/how-housing-matters-article/</guid>
      <description>The Urban Institute&amp;rsquo;s How Housing Matters website has published an enlightening piece summarizing the current state of nationwide eviction data-gathering, as well as describing the critical role this data can play in informing public policy. As Eviction Lab Principal Investigator Matthew Desmond explains,
“Eviction is a giant problem that we only know is giant because of being in touch with communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arlington Reads - &#34;Evicted&#34; by Matthew Desmond</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-05-17-arlington-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 22:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-05-17-arlington-library/</guid>
      <description>Matthew Desmond takes readers into the poorest neighborhoods of Milwaukee and tells the stories of eight families who struggle to keep a roof over their heads as they face extreme poverty, eviction and economic exploitation.
The fates of these families are in the hands of two landlords: Sherrena Tarver, a former schoolteacher turned inner-city entrepreneur, and Tobin Charney, who runs one of the worst trailer parks in Milwaukee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home and Hope: A Community Call to Action</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-05-16-jfsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 22:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-05-16-jfsm/</guid>
      <description>As part of its 150th Anniversary Celebration, Jewish Family Services (JFS) convenes community stakeholders to address the urgent need for safe and affordable housing, which has emerged as a leading social justice issue of our time.
JFS proudly welcomes Professor Matthew Desmond, whose local research, as chronicled in the Pulitzer-Prize-winning book, Evicted – Poverty and Profit in the American City, cast a spotlight on a complex problem that demands collaborative solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Estimates: Eviction in America</title>
      <link>/national-estimates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 16:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/national-estimates/</guid>
      <description>Since the Eviction Lab’s inception, we’ve been in constant pursuit of a seemingly simple question: how many evictions take place in the United States each year? After countless hours of data collection and research, we are finally able to produce some of the first estimates of the national prevalence of eviction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pathstone Presents: Provoking Thought</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-05-09-pathstone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 22:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-05-09-pathstone/</guid>
      <description>Building on our nearly five decades of success in Community Development, Workforce Development and Emergency Support services, PathStone is excited to launch PathStone Presents - Provoking Thought!, an opportunity to meet and interact with thought leaders engaged in addressing persistent poverty. Our inaugural luncheon will feature Dr. Matthew Desmond, Pulitzer Prize-winning author of Evicted: Poverty and Profit in the American City”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tackling Poverty Today</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-05-08-uja-federation-ny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 22:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-05-08-uja-federation-ny/</guid>
      <description>Join UJA-Federation and other leaders in the nonprofit, public, and for-profit sectors as we come together to learn, foster collaborations, and strategize about how to best address poverty in the greater New York community today.
Featured topics:
 Social enterprises addressing housing, hunger, and unemployment Groundbreaking government policies aimed at fighting poverty Tackling poverty through technological innovations Raising awareness through media and publishing  Keynote Speaker: Matthew Desmond Pulitzer Prize-Winning Author of Evicted: Poverty and Profit in the American City</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Partnered With Mapbox to Visualize Evictions Nationwide</title>
      <link>/updates/blog/how-we-built-with-mapbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 23:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/blog/how-we-built-with-mapbox/</guid>
      <description>When Matthew Desmond and his Eviction Lab research team offered us the task of mapping and visualizing their first-of-its-kind database of eviction statistics, we (the web team) were excited, honored, and humbled. And then, when things began to get real and the project took shape, we drew a collective deep breath as we grasped the magnitude of the challenges ahead of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eviction Lab Media Guide</title>
      <link>/media-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 15:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/media-guide/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Eviction Lab. We hope you will engage with the data we’ve been able to gather and make public. Here are some considerations to keep in mind as you interpret our numbers.
On the Map &amp;amp; Data section of our website, we have included a national database of eviction estimates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community in Crisis: Understanding Housing Insecurity</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-04-19-nku/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 22:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-04-19-nku/</guid>
      <description>Join Matthew Desmond, sociologist and Pulitzer Prize winner, as he discusses his powerful book, Evicted: Poverty and Profit in the American City.
RSVP: By April 18, 2018 to https://nku.eventsair.com/evicted/april19</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Evicted&#34; Takes Form in New Museum Exhibit</title>
      <link>/updates/blog/evicted-natl-building-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 23:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/blog/evicted-natl-building-museum/</guid>
      <description>First there was the book Evicted, with its heartbreaking stories of families and individuals struggling to maintain stable shelter. Next came the release of The Eviction Lab&amp;rsquo;s database, revealing the often-surprising scale and span of the eviction crisis. Now eviction and its consequences are explored in a 3-dimensional, immersive presentation at The National Building Museum&amp;rsquo;s Evicted exhibition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eviction Lab Media Coverage Roundup</title>
      <link>/updates/media/first-week-media-roundup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 15:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/media/first-week-media-roundup/</guid>
      <description>During The Eviction Lab&amp;rsquo;s first week online, we were encouraged to see interest in our dataset and website—and the eviction epidemic it reveals—from a number of major national media outlets.
The New York Times profiled Richmond, VA (#2 in our Eviction Rankings) to demonstrate the effect of its staggering eviction numbers on residents of one city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evicted: The Exhibition</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-04-14-national-building-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-04-14-national-building-museum/</guid>
      <description>The National Building Museum announces a new, ground-breaking exhibition exploring the causes and impacts of eviction.
A collaboration with Matthew Desmond, Professor of Sociology at Princeton University, a MacArthur “Genius” Fellow, and best-selling author, Evicted will offer an immersive experience bringing our visitors into the world of low-income renter eviction. With unique design elements and striking graphics, the exhibition will challenge adults and youth to face the enormity of a difficult subject, while providing context and a call to action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh Air: First-Ever Evictions Database Shows &#39;We&#39;re In the Middle Of A Housing Crisis&#39;</title>
      <link>/updates/media/fresh-air-interview-eviction-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 15:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/media/fresh-air-interview-eviction-lab/</guid>
      <description>Today on NPR&amp;rsquo;s Fresh Air, Terry Gross interviews Matthew Desmond, who helps put the eviction crisis in perspective.
Desmond, on the estimate that 2.3 million people faced eviction in 2016:
&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s twice the number of Americans that die in car accidents every day. That&amp;rsquo;s twice the number of people who get arrested for drug offenses every year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Eviction Data: Putting Residential Instability Numbers into Public Hands</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-04-12-urban-institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-04-12-urban-institute/</guid>
      <description>Join the Urban Institute for a discussion about a new data source on evictions in the US and its value for community response.
A shortage of affordable rental housing leaves millions of US households struggling to pay rent and avoid eviction. As documented by the sociologist and ethnographer Matthew Desmond and other housing scholars, evictions destabilize renters’ current housing and affect their work, health, education, and future housing options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marketplace: Millions of Americans are evicted every year — and not just in big cities</title>
      <link>/updates/media/marketplace-npr-eviction-lab-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 15:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/media/marketplace-npr-eviction-lab-story/</guid>
      <description>NPR&amp;rsquo;s Marketplace features an interview between host David Brancaccio and Matthew Desmond, detailing the shocking volume of evictions in the US, their deeper causes, and how the hotspots of the eviction crisis are often places you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t expect.
Desmond: &amp;ldquo;If you read the news, you&amp;rsquo;d think that the housing crisis is basically in Seattle, and New York City, and San Francisco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The New York Times Profiles The Eviction Lab</title>
      <link>/updates/media/nytimes-evictions-richmond/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 15:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/media/nytimes-evictions-richmond/</guid>
      <description>The New York Times has chosen Richmond, VA (listed at #2 in our Eviction Rankings) as the focus of a front-page story, which also profiles Matthew Desmond and The Eviction Lab&amp;rsquo;s work in collecting over 83 million eviction records from across the country.
The article details the &amp;ldquo;churning machine&amp;rdquo; of evictions in Richmond, driven by a court system that is often as inscrutable to tenants as it is unsparingly efficient in rendering judgments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Eviction Lab.  Let’s Get to Work!</title>
      <link>/updates/blog/welcome-to-the-eviction-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 23:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/blog/welcome-to-the-eviction-lab/</guid>
      <description>Imagine if we didn’t know how many Americans were incarcerated each year or how many dropped out of high school, got divorced, or lost their job. If we don’t know how big a problem something is, where it is happening, or how many families are touched by it, then how can we begin the critical work of finding solutions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eviction Lab Teacher&#39;s Guide</title>
      <link>/teacher-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 13:13:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teacher-guide/</guid>
      <description>Evictionlab.org can be a resource for teachers working with students on data analysis, public policy, social studies, and more. Students in service organizations or those who act as representatives to local governing bodies may also benefit from learning about housing issues in their community.
We would love to hear from teachers who use evictionlab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Methodology Report</title>
      <link>/updates/research/our-methodology-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 16:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/research/our-methodology-report/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, renters’ housing costs have far outpaced their incomes, driving a nationwide affordability crisis. Current data from the American Housing Survey show that most poor renting families spend at least 50 percent of their income on housing costs. Under these conditions, 1 millions of Americans today are at risk of losing their homes through eviction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Note to Researchers</title>
      <link>/updates/research/note-to-researchers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 15:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/research/note-to-researchers/</guid>
      <description>As mentioned in our Welcome blog post, we&amp;rsquo;re offering the full Eviction Lab dataset to enable research on housing, eviction, and inequality in America.
If you use Eviction Lab data, please let us know! Share your findings with us by emailing research@evictionlab.org. We may feature your study on this website and look forward to learning from your work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us | Eviction Lab</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/page-text/meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/page-text/meta/</guid>
      <description>We thank the following Citizen Researchers for helping us build America’s first national database of evictions by providing original data to the Eviction Lab. If you would like to share eviction data with us, please email research@evictionlab.org.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>/contact/page-content/form1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/page-content/form1/</guid>
      <description>To get in touch, please use the form below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Form</title>
      <link>/contact/page-content/form2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/page-content/form2/</guid>
      <description>You can also email us directly regarding
 Help requests or site feedback at help@evictionlab.org
 Research inquiries at research@evictionlab.org Media inquiries at press@evictionlab.org General questions or comments at info@evictionlab.org  If you would like to merge your data with The Eviction Lab&amp;rsquo;s dataset, please use our Data Merge Application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help &amp; FAQ | Eviction Lab</title>
      <link>/help-faq/page-content/meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/help-faq/page-content/meta/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methods | Eviction Lab</title>
      <link>/methods/page-content/meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/methods/page-content/meta/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Upcoming Events</title>
      <link>/updates/events/2018-10-10-neighbor-to-neighbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/events/2018-10-10-neighbor-to-neighbor/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>