<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Eviction Lab</title>
    <link>/updates/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Eviction Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:02 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/updates/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Housing Policy Scorecard Methodology</title>
      <link>/covid-housing-scorecard-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 16:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-housing-scorecard-methods/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
To prevent the deleterious health consequences of eviction and an escalating economic crisis during the COVID-19 outbreak, U.S. states are beginning to pursue strategies to ensure safe, decent, and stable housing during and after the pandemic. To evaluate state responses, the Eviction Lab and Columbia Law School’s Professor Emily Benfer have developed a policy scorecard for each state, distilling the contents of thousands of newly-released emergency orders, declarations, and legislation into a clear set of critical measures included in, and left out of, state-level pandemic responses related to eviction and housing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Estimates: Eviction in America</title>
      <link>/national-estimates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 16:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/national-estimates/</guid>
      <description>Since the Eviction Lab’s inception, we’ve been in constant pursuit of a seemingly simple question: how many evictions take place in the United States each year? After countless hours of data collection and research, we are finally able to produce some of the first estimates of the national prevalence of eviction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Methodology Report</title>
      <link>/updates/research/our-methodology-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 16:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/research/our-methodology-report/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, renters’ housing costs have far outpaced their incomes, driving a nationwide affordability crisis. Current data from the American Housing Survey show that most poor renting families spend at least 50 percent of their income on housing costs. Under these conditions, 1 millions of Americans today are at risk of losing their homes through eviction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Note to Researchers</title>
      <link>/updates/research/note-to-researchers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 15:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/research/note-to-researchers/</guid>
      <description>As mentioned in our Welcome blog post, we&amp;rsquo;re offering the full Eviction Lab dataset to enable research on housing, eviction, and inequality in America.
If you use Eviction Lab data, please let us know! Share your findings with us by emailing research@evictionlab.org. We may feature your study on this website and look forward to learning from your work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>