<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research Team Bios on Eviction Lab</title>
    <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research Team Bios on Eviction Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/about/page-content/research-team-bios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Matthew Desmond</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/matthew-desmond/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/matthew-desmond/</guid>
      <description>Matthew Desmond is a Professor in the Department of Sociology at Princeton University. After receiving his Ph.D. in 2010 from the University of Wisconsin at Madison, he joined the Harvard Society of Fellows as a Junior Fellow. He is the author of four books, including Evicted: Poverty and Profit in the American City (2016), which won the Pulitzer Prize, National Book Critics Circle Award, and Carnegie Medal, and PEN / John Kenneth Galbraith Award for Nonfiction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Hendrickson</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/james-hendrickson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/james-hendrickson/</guid>
      <description>James is a recent graduate of the University of Michigan, where he obtained a B.A. in Public Policy with a focus on Applied Statistics and Labor Policy. He has worked for several public interest nonprofits, such as the ACLU and the NEA, where he developed a deep interest in the intersection of statistical analysis and policy. Currently serving as a Research Specialist with the Eviction Lab, James seeks to better understand how the current legal infrastructure affects housing instability, as well as how policymakers can best craft housing assistance solutions that will benefit their own communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LAVAR EDMONDS</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/lavar-edmonds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/lavar-edmonds/</guid>
      <description>Lavar Edmonds received a Bachelor of Science in economics from the University of Mary Washington and a master’s in Education Policy from the University of Pennsylvania. Guided by experiences as a high school math teacher, his background includes using quantitative methods and big data to study pervasive social inequalities, particularly in education. In college, he worked as the data analyst for the school’s Student Transition Program, studying academic outcomes for first-generation and traditionally underrepresented minority students at the university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley Gromis</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/ashley-gromis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:52:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/ashley-gromis/</guid>
      <description>Ashley joined the Eviction Lab as a postdoctoral research associate after completing her Ph.D. in Sociology at the University of California, Los Angeles. Her dissertation research examined the formation and consequences of spatial clustering of children with non-medical exemptions to school vaccine requirements in California. More broadly, her research interests focus on how social networks and local communities provide the social context for individual decisions and events that aggregate to form macro-level patterns across space and time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peter Hepburn</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/peter-hepburn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/peter-hepburn/</guid>
      <description>Peter joined the Eviction Lab as an Associate Professional Specialist after completing his doctorate in Sociology and Demography at the University of California, Berkeley. Peter&amp;rsquo;s research examines the ways that employment practices and public policies affect children and low-income families. His dissertation analyzed the relationships between parental working schedules, household structure, and childcare arrangements. He has also studied the effects of mass imprisonment on kin networks, exposure to subfelony criminal justice in New York City, and trajectories of employment and disability among American workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Katie Krywokulski</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/katie-krywokulski/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 03:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/katie-krywokulski/</guid>
      <description>Katie received an MA in English Language and Literature from the University of Chicago in 2016. Her research interests included religion and the literary history of consent eighteenth and nineteenth century America. She taught courses titled “Death and Dying in Early America” and “Women Possessed: Religion, Gender, and Sexuality,” as well as first year writing classes. Her interests related to the Eviction Lab include gender based housing discrimination, and how to improve housing stability for people affected by addiction and mental health issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lillian Leung</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/lillian-leung/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/lillian-leung/</guid>
      <description>Lillian is a recent graduate from New York University’s Stern School of Business, where she studied Economics and Global Business and minored in Social Entrepreneurship. She grew up in Hong Kong and has lived in Chicago and New York. Drawing on her experiences living in cities, her undergraduate thesis used General Social Survey data to explore the effect of housing prices on perceptions of inequality. She has also worked with various surveying methods conducting program evaluations for non-profits and customer research at Squarespace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Porton</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/adam-porton/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/adam-porton/</guid>
      <description>Adam is a research specialist with the Eviction Lab. He received his bachelor’s degree in Sociology with a concentration in analysis and research from the University of Wisconsin-Madison. Prior to working at Princeton, he supported social science research projects at the Center for Financial Security and the Environmental Resources Center. He also has a background in political organizing and community non-profits. At the eviction lab, Adam’s research interests include exploring the intersection between affordable housing policy, community health, and cooperative economic institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>