<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Eviction Lab</title>
    <link>/updates/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Eviction Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:20 -0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/updates/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 and Changing Eviction Policies Around the Nation</title>
      <link>/covid-eviction-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 16:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/covid-eviction-policies/</guid>
      <description>As the world seeks to contain the COVID-19 pandemic, policymakers across the U.S. are responding to the heightened insecurity so many face.
This new table details where municipalities, states, and the federal government have taken action. We will be continually updating the table and welcome tips regarding what your community is putting into place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article: Eviction Data Can Keep Cities from “Designing Policy in the Dark”</title>
      <link>/updates/blog/how-housing-matters-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 08:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/blog/how-housing-matters-article/</guid>
      <description>The Urban Institute&amp;rsquo;s How Housing Matters website has published an enlightening piece summarizing the current state of nationwide eviction data-gathering, as well as describing the critical role this data can play in informing public policy. As Eviction Lab Principal Investigator Matthew Desmond explains,
“Eviction is a giant problem that we only know is giant because of being in touch with communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Partnered With Mapbox to Visualize Evictions Nationwide</title>
      <link>/updates/blog/how-we-built-with-mapbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 23:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/blog/how-we-built-with-mapbox/</guid>
      <description>When Matthew Desmond and his Eviction Lab research team offered us the task of mapping and visualizing their first-of-its-kind database of eviction statistics, we (the web team) were excited, honored, and humbled. And then, when things began to get real and the project took shape, we drew a collective deep breath as we grasped the magnitude of the challenges ahead of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Evicted&#34; Takes Form in New Museum Exhibit</title>
      <link>/updates/blog/evicted-natl-building-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 23:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/blog/evicted-natl-building-museum/</guid>
      <description>First there was the book Evicted, with its heartbreaking stories of families and individuals struggling to maintain stable shelter. Next came the release of The Eviction Lab&amp;rsquo;s database, revealing the often-surprising scale and span of the eviction crisis. Now eviction and its consequences are explored in a 3-dimensional, immersive presentation at The National Building Museum&amp;rsquo;s Evicted exhibition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Eviction Lab.  Let’s Get to Work!</title>
      <link>/updates/blog/welcome-to-the-eviction-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 23:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/blog/welcome-to-the-eviction-lab/</guid>
      <description>Imagine if we didn’t know how many Americans were incarcerated each year or how many dropped out of high school, got divorced, or lost their job. If we don’t know how big a problem something is, where it is happening, or how many families are touched by it, then how can we begin the critical work of finding solutions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eviction Lab Teacher&#39;s Guide</title>
      <link>/teacher-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 13:13:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teacher-guide/</guid>
      <description>Evictionlab.org can be a resource for teachers working with students on data analysis, public policy, social studies, and more. Students in service organizations or those who act as representatives to local governing bodies may also benefit from learning about housing issues in their community.
We would love to hear from teachers who use evictionlab.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>