<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research Team Bios on Eviction Lab</title>
    <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research Team Bios on Eviction Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 20:43:49 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/about/page-content/research-team-bios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Matthew Desmond</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/matthew-desmond/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/matthew-desmond/</guid>
      <description>Matthew Desmond is the Maurice P. During Professor of Sociology at Princeton University. After receiving his Ph.D. in 2010 from the University of Wisconsin at Madison, he joined the Harvard Society of Fellows as a Junior Fellow. He is the author of four books, including Evicted: Poverty and Profit in the American City (2016), which won the Pulitzer Prize, National Book Critics Circle Award, and Carnegie Medal, and PEN / John Kenneth Galbraith Award for Nonfiction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helena Najm</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/helena-najm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/helena-najm/</guid>
      <description>Helena received her HBSc from the University of Toronto in 2017, and graduated from Columbia University&amp;rsquo;s MA in Global Thought program in 2019. She has worked at the nexus of health, politics and social inequality in academic and public service capacities, and is broadly interested in researching social welfare policy, urban inequality, citizenship and social stratification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anne Kat Alexander</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/anne-kat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/anne-kat/</guid>
      <description>Anne Kat is a recent graduate of Brandeis University, where she received a BA in English and Creative Writing. She is the Faculty Assistant in the Eviction Lab. Her bachelor&amp;rsquo;s thesis considered issues of chronic low mood and hopelessness in early modern poetry, which may be why she sticks to reading murder mysteries and YA these days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alieza Durana</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/alieza-durana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/alieza-durana/</guid>
      <description>Alieza Durana is a journalist and media impact expert helping to increase the reach and impact of stories. Her passion for addressing social and income inequalities has taken her around the world in pursuit of the data and stories that can move policy and culture forward. She writes and leads media strategy for The Eviction Lab in partnership with the Economic Hardship Reporting Project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LAVAR EDMONDS</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/lavar-edmonds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/lavar-edmonds/</guid>
      <description>Lavar Edmonds is a research specialist with the Eviction Lab. Guided by experiences as a high school math teacher, his research broadly centers around inequality, particularly in education. In college, he worked as the data analyst for the school’s Student Transition Program, studying academic outcomes for first-generation and traditionally underrepresented minority students at the university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joe Fish</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/joe-fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/joe-fish/</guid>
      <description>Joe received his bachelor’s degree in Economics and Applied Math from Macalester College. A San Francisco native, his senior thesis used a survival analysis framework to explore the effect of zip code level tech growth on San Francisco eviction rates. As a researcher, he hopes to establish causal relationships between the effects of wealth consolidation and income inequality on eviction rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashley Gromis</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/ashley-gromis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:52:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/ashley-gromis/</guid>
      <description>Ashley joined the Eviction Lab as a postdoctoral research associate after completing her Ph.D. in Sociology at the University of California, Los Angeles. Her dissertation research examined the formation and consequences of spatial clustering of children with non-medical exemptions to school vaccine requirements in California. More broadly, her research interests focus on how social networks and local communities provide the social context for individual decisions and events that aggregate to form macro-level patterns across space and time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peter Hepburn</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/peter-hepburn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/peter-hepburn/</guid>
      <description>Peter joined the Eviction Lab as an Associate Professional Specialist after completing his doctorate in Sociology and Demography at the University of California, Berkeley. Peter&amp;rsquo;s research examines the ways that employment practices and public policies affect children and low-income families. His dissertation analyzed the relationships between parental working schedules, household structure, and childcare arrangements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aparna Howlader</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/aparna-howlader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/aparna-howlader/</guid>
      <description>Aparna completed her Ph.D. at the Department of Agricultural and Consumer Economics at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign. Her dissertation research studies the relationship between land conservation policies and economic development. A large part of her current research is devoted to studying the extent to which early land conservation policies in the USA affect later economic and environmental conditions in the Great Plains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Katie Krywokulski</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/katie-krywokulski/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 03:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/katie-krywokulski/</guid>
      <description>Katie received an MA in English Language and Literature from the University of Chicago in 2016. Her research interests included religion and the literary history of consent eighteenth and nineteenth century America. She taught courses titled “Death and Dying in Early America” and “Women Possessed: Religion, Gender, and Sexuality,” as well as first year writing classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renee Louis</title>
      <link>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/renee-louis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/page-content/research-team-bios/renee-louis/</guid>
      <description>Renee received her B.A. from Princeton University where she concentrated in Sociology and received a certificate in Statistics and Machine Learning. Her undergraduate research endeavors ranged from examining nonprofit Twitter behavior, analyzing attitudes towards inequality across forty years of survey data, as well as studying the experiences of student dining hall workers on campus.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>